Finding Aid for Stellanova Osborn papers, 1907-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Stellanova Osborn papers 1907-1988
Osborn, Stellanova, 1894-1988.
86727 Aa 2
Wife of Chase S. Osborn, leader in the Atlantic Union Movement, and officer in the Atlantic Union Conference, the International Movement for Atlantic Union, and Federal Union, Inc. Correspondence, diaries and other materials concerning her professional interests, especially her work for world peace through international cooperation.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
40 linear feet
The collection (donor no. 2668 ) came to the library in several accessions beginning 1958. The last accession was received in 1992.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Stella Brunt Osborn was born on July 31, 1894 in Hamilton, Canada. She finished elementary school in 1908, and subsequently went to work at the age of fifteen as a stenographer. She eventually completed her high school education through night classes in Toledo, Ohio. In 1916 she entered the University of Michigan, graduating summa cum laude and Phi Beta Kappa in 1922. In 1930 she received a master's degree in Medieval English Literature, and in 1978, an honorary Doctorate of Letters, both from the University of Michigan.
In the years 1923 to 1930 she worked as an editor for various publications. In 1931, she became the adopted daughter of Chase S. Osborn, ex-Governor of Michigan, and collaborated with him on five books: The Conquest of a Continent, 1939; Schoolcraft-Longfellow-Hiawatha, 1942; Hiawatha with its Original Indian Legends, 1944; Errors in the U.S. Official Area Figures, 1945; and Northwood Sketches, 1949. On her own Stella Osborn wrote Eighty and on, 1941; A tale of Possum Poke in Possum Lane, 1946; Balsam Boughs, 1949; Jasmine Springs, 1953; Polly Cadotte, 1955; Beside the cabin, 1957; Iron and Arbutus, 1962; and Summer Songs on the St. Mary's, 1982. On April 9, 1949 her adoption was annulled and she then married Chase Osborn.
Since Chase Osborn's death (April 11, 1949), Stella Osborn's main interest has been in a number of international world peace organizations for which she has worked as a volunteer for nearly thirty years. These include the Atlantic Union Committee (founder and chairman, Michigan branch), the International Movement for Atlantic Union (founder of the North American branch; secretary 1958-1965), Federal Union, Inc. (board member, 1962), International Association for Federal Union (founder, honorary vice-president, 1972). She was also active in the Capitol Club of the Business and Professional Women's Club, and was a Distinguished Professor of Humanities at Abraham Baldwin Agricultural College in Tipton, Georgia. She retired in 1972, but maintained an active interest and correspondence with these organization.
Stella Osborn died in Sault St. Marie in March 1988, where she had moved from Poulan, Georgia in 1980. In the last years of her life, she continued a lively interest in world affairs, actively corresponding with friends and with colleagues from the various peace organizations with which she had been involved.
The Stella Osborn collection was received in multiple accessions. The bulk of the papers were received from her home in Georgia (1958) and her office in Washington D.C. (1972). These materials documenting her entire career were organized into seven series: Biographical; Correspondence; Personal and miscellaneous; Atlantic Union Committee and related; Business and Professional Women's Club; Sound recordings; and Index card files. An extremely active woman with many interests and causes, Stella Osborn continued to add to her papers with a later accession in 1983. Following her death, the executor of her estate and other friends added to the collection with materials which she had retained for whatever reason or which had been in storage. There is obviously some overlap in these later materials and the files received previously. The purpose of the Summary Contents List (see below) is to draw like materials together.
The 1992 accession was more fully described than the earlier papers. This accession includes biographical notes and clippings about Stella Osborn and Chase Osborn. There is, in addition, personal and organizational correspondence, financial and estate records (1970-1988), land deeds for the Osborn holdings in Georgia and Michigan, organizational material for the Federal Union and the Atlantic Union Committee, manuscripts of poetry, prose, and political essays (including some material by Chase Osborn), and Stella Osborn's diaries (1982-87). The collection includes childhood photographs of Stella Osborn and photographs of her parents and grandparents. Two copies of a videotape about the Osborn farm in Georgia, Possum Poke, are included here as well.
Much of this accession documents the last few years of Stella Osborn's life, after her move to a retirement home in Sault St. Marie Michigan, years during which she maintained an interest in people and world peace organizations, and in documenting her own and Chase Osborn's place in history. While the bulk of correspondence here is for 1982, 1983, and 1987, some earlier correspondence is included as well. Of interest to university historians is the topical correspondence file on Robert Frost's visit to Michigan. Stella Osborn's lifelong friendship with Yuki Otsuki is documented by their extensive correspondence, a series of letters beautifully written and presented that recall earlier days, including student life.
The collection contains some material of interest to researchers interested in Chase Osborn, including the series of land transfers and deeds which document Chase and Stella Osborn's extensive holdings in Georgia and Michigan, and their gifts of land to various charities and institutions. Also included is some Chase Osborn correspondence and copies of articles he wrote about his extensive travels in Africa. Chase Osborn's 1938 "Longfellow Birthday Book" contains the birth dates of his ancestors. Several letters from 1936 pertain to Chase Osborn's involvement in the movement to build the Mackinac Bridge.
Of special interest to researchers interested in Stella Osborn and her role in various world peace organizations are her unpublished autobiographical manuscripts and files. Also of interest are her diaries, where she continued to record her ideas about politics and her memories.
Summary Contents Lists
Accessions, 1958 and 1971-1972 [boxes 1-27]
Biographical material [box 1]
Correspondence, 1916-1982 [boxes 1-13]
Personal and miscellaneous
Schedules, notes on telephone conversations, various writings [box 14]
Personal press releases [box 15]
Speeches [box 15]
Clippings [box 15]
Poetry [box 15]
Income tax files [box 15]
Diaries [box 16]
Student notebooks, account books, etc. (U-M and others) [box 16]
Atlantic Union Committee and related [boxes 17-24]
Business and Professional Women's Club activities [box 24]
Sound tapes [box 25]
Card files [boxes 25-27]
1983 Accession [boxes 28-34]
Biographical material [box 28]
Correspondence, 1918-1983 [boxes 28-31]
Organizations [box 31]
Topical file [boxes 31-32]
Writings (autobiography, poetry, prose) [box 32]
Diaries [box 33]
Visual materials [box 34]
1992 Accession [boxes 35-38]
Biographical and Autobiographical Material (including Chase Osborn) [box 35]
Correspondence, 1960-1987 [box 35]
Financial and Business Affairs, 1920-1985 [boxes 35-36]
Peace Organizations, 1970-1983 [box 36]
Manuscripts and Research Notes [box 36]
Chase Osborn materials, 1913-1949 [box 37]
Diaries, account books, day books, 1930-1987 [box 37-38]
Card Indices [box 38]
Subjects:
Atlantic Union (U.S.); Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Osborn, Stellanova, 1894-1988.; Peace--Societies, etc.; Social reformers--United States.; Sugar Island (Mich.); United Nations.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Georgia--Work.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Atlantic Union (U.S.); Bentley Historical Library.; Boy Scouts.; Brunt family.; Clothing and dress.; Dogs.; Duck Island (Chippewa County, Mich.); Dwellings.; Ewen (Mich.); Families.; Helen Handy Newberry Residence (University of Michigan); Historical markers--Indiana.; Indiana--Historical markers.; Interiors.; Jackson (Mich.)--Prison facilities.; Lee family.; Living rooms.; Log cabins.; Monuments and memorials.; Motion picture devices--1947.; Native Americans--Michigan--Arts and crafts.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Osborn, Stellanova, 1894-1988.; Poulon (Ga.); Prison facilities--Michigan--Jackson.; State Prison of Southern Michigan.; Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Stylus (University of Michigan); Television broadcasting--United States.; University of Michigan. Class of 1922.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae--Anniversaries, etc.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; Women.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Contributors:
Achilles, Theodore C. (Theodore Carter), 1905-1986; Adams, Paul L. (Paul Lincoln), 1908-; Adenauer, Paul.; Adler, O.; Aly, Bower, 1903-1977; Ashley, Thomas William Ludlow, 1923-; Baker, Frank C., Mrs.; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956.; Bartlett, Lynn M. (Lynn Mahlon), 1904-1970.; Beck, Joseph, 1887-; Beeson, Lewis.; Bennett, John B. (John Bonifas), 1905-1964.; Bentley, Alvin M. (Alvin Morell), 1918-1969.; Billotte, Pierre, 1906-; Birrenbach, Kurt, 1907-; Blackwelder, Justin.; Blitch, Iris, 1912-1993.; Block, Herbert, 1909-2001.; Bonisteel, Roscoe O. (Roscoe Osmond), b. 1888.; Breckinbridge, John Bayne, 1913-; Brown, Clarence J., 1893-1965.; Brown, Garry Eldridge, 1923-1998; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Bumgardner, Eleanor M. (Eleanor Margaret); Bundy, McGeorge.; Burke, Arleigh A., 1901-1996; Caldwell, Harmon White, 1899-1977; Campbell, Albert A.; Capehart, Homer E. (Homer Earl), 1897-1979.; Carlson, Frank, 1893-1987; Case, James Herbert, 1906-1965; Chamberlain, Charles E. (Charles Ernest), 1917-2002; Charlesworth, James C. (James Clyde), 1900-1974; Church, Frank.; Church, Michael P. (Michael Paul), 1907-; Clark, Frank Monroe, 1915-; Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius DuBignon), 1897-1978.; Cleveland, Harlan.; Clevenger, Raymond Francis, 1926-; Coleman, John Strider, 1897-1958.; Cooper, John Sherman, 1901-1991; Corbett, Robert J. (Robert James), 1905-1971.; Cousins, Norman.; Crawford, Fred L., 1888-1957.; Cunningham, Sarah Jane.; Curtis, Thomas B. (Thomas Bradford), 1911-1993; Dahlberg, Edwin T. (Edwin Theodore), 1892-1986.; Dennis, Don.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Diefenbaker, John G., 1895-1979.; Dingell, John D. (John David), 1894-1955.; Dirksen, Everett McKinley.; Dodd, Thomas J. (Thomas Joseph), 1907-1971.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Douglas, William O. (William Orville), 1898-1980.; Drury, Newton B., 1889-; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.; Earle, Clifford.; Eddy, Gerald E. (Gerald Ernest), 1907-1977; Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon, 1897-1977.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Elliott, Edward C. (Edward Charles), 1874-1960.; Ellrick, Charles Burke, 1908-; Ellsworth, Robert.; Esch, Marvin Lionel, 1927-; Fairclough, Ellen Louks.; Fanget, Louis A.; Farnsley, Charles Roland Peaslee, 1907-; Ferguson, Charles W. (Charles Wright), 1901-1987.; Ferguson, Homer, 1889-1982.; Field, George, 1904-; Findley, Paul, 1921-; Fitzpatrick, John J., 1914-; Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-2010.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Ford, Henry, 1917-1987.; Fraser, Donald Mackay, 1924-; Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-1995.; Gavin, Leon H.; George, Walter F. (Walter Franklin), 1878-1957.; Gillette, Guy M.; Glick, Brian.; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998.; Gordon, Archibald, Sir.; Gore, Albert, 1907-1998.; Green, Theodore Francis, 1867-1966.; Griffin, Robert P. (Robert Paul), 1923-2015; Griffiths, Martha W. (Martha Wright), 1912-2003.; Gruenther, Alfred M. (Alfred Maximilian), 1899-1983; Guest, Edgar A. (Edgar Albert), 1881-1959.; Hanes, John W. (John Wesley), 1892-1987; Hardy, Ralph W.; Hare, James M. (James McNeil), 1910-1980; Harkness, Douglas Scott, 1903-; Harris, Frederick Brown.; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Hartigan, John D.; Hatcher, Harlan, 1898-1998.; Hatfield, Mark O., 1922-2011; Heard, Alexander.; Hellyer, Paul Theodore, 1923-; Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966.; Hildebrandt, Herbert W.; Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967.; Holbrook, Sabra.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Hovde, Frederick L., 1908-1983; Hughes, Sarah T. (Sarah Tilghman), 1896-1985; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986.; Jeffries, Edward, 1900-1950; Johanneson, Alexander.; Johnson, Lady Bird, 1912-2007.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kee, John.; Kefauver, Estes, 1903-1963.; Kefauver, Nancy Patterson.; Kelly, Harry F. (Harry Francis), 1895-1971.; Kelsey, William Kline, 1885-; Kessenich, Michiels van, baron.; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Knox, Victor Alfred, 1899-; Lausche, Frank John, 1895-1990; Lawrence, David, 1888-; Long, Russell B.; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987.; Lunsford, Frank J.; McAllister, Thomas Francis, 1896-; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-2005.; McGee, Gale W. (Gale William), 1915-1992.; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922-2012; McGrath, Tom J.; Machrowicz, Thaddeus Michael, 1899-1970; MacLachlan, James Angell, 1891-1967; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Macmillan, Harold, 1894-1986.; McNamara, Patrick Vincent, 1894-1966.; Marc, Alexandre.; Marshall, Charles Burton, 1908-1999; Martin, Paul, 1903-1992; Mason, Philip P. (Philip Parker), 1927-; Meader, George, 1907-1994; Meagher, John Patrick, 1922-; Merchant, Livingston T. (Livingston Tallmadge), 1903-1976; Michener, Daniel Roland, 1900-; Milliken, Helen, 1922-; Milliken, William G., 1922-; Mills, Wilbur D. (Wilbur Daigh), 1909-1992; Mondale, Walter F., 1928-; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; Moore, Arthur J. (Arthur James), 1888-1974.; Moore, Walden.; Morgan, Thomas Ellsworth, 1906-; Morrison, William Angus, 1914-; Morse, Wayne L. (Wayne Lyman), 1900-1974.; Morton, Rogers C., 1914-; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Murrow, Edward R.; Muskie, Edmund S., 1914-1996; Nicholson, Patrick.; Nicholson, Robert Lawrence, 1908-1985; Niehuss, Marvin Lemmon, 1903-2003; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Norstad, Lauris, 1907-1988; North, Roy M. (Roy Moses), 1889-1975; O'Hara, James G.; Oppenheimer, William Henry, 1883-; Osborne, Lithgow, 1892-1980; Parsons, Geoffrey, 1908-1981; Pearson, Lester B.; Percy, Charles H., 1919-2011; Peterson, Elly Maude, 1914-2008; Pêtrequin, Odette.; Pilcher, John L. (John Leonard), 1898-1981; Plant, Marcus L., 1911-1984; Potter, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1916-1979.; Priest, J. Percy.; Quimby, Thomas H. E. (Thomas Howard Emerson), 1918-1998; Rabaut, Louis Charles, 1886-1961.; Rice, Warner Grenelle, 1899-; Richards, James P. (James Prioleau), 1894-1979; Riegle, Donald W., 1938-; Roberts, Owen J. (Owen Josephus), 1875-1955.; Robertson, Wishart McLea, 1891-1967; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1912-1973.; Roijen, J. H. van (Jan Herman); Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Romney, Lenore LaFount.; Roosevelt, James, 1907-1991; Ruppe, Philip E.; Rusk, Dean, 1909-1994; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970.; Russell, Richard B. (Richard Brevard), 1897-1971.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Rutledge, Wiley Blount, 1894-1949.; Sewell, John.; Shawcross, Hartly, 1902-; Shotwell, James Thomson, 1874-1965.; Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-1984; Smith, Allan Frederick, 1911-; Smith, Margaret Chase, 1897-1995.; Spaak, Paul Henri, 1899-1972.; Sparkman, John, 1899-1985.; Spock, Benjamin, 1903-1998.; Stanford, George Alonzo, 1917-; Stanley, Augustus Owsley, 1867-1958.; Stanton, Frank, 1908-2006; Stason, E. Blythe (Edwin Blythe), 1891-1972.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1930-; Strauss, Franz Josef, 1915-1988; Streit, Clarence K. (Clarence Kirshman), 1896-1986; Sulzberger, C. L. (Cyrus Leo), 1912-1993.; Swainson, John B. (John Burley), 1925-1994.; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953.; Talmadge, Herman E. (Herman Eugene), 1913-2002.; Thomas, Elbert Duncan, 1883-1953.; Thomson, J. A.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tunney, James Joseph, 1897-; Tuttle, Elbert P. (Elbert Parr), 1897-1996; Udall, Morris K.; Udall, Stewart L.; Urey, Harold Clayton, 1893-1981.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Vander Jagt, Guy, 1931-2007.; Vander Velde, Lewis G. (Lewis George), 1890-1975.; Wagner, Rudolph.; Wallace, Richard J.; Walther, G. von.; Warner, Robert M. (Robert Mark), 1927-2007.; Washburn, Abbott McConnell, 1915-; Weltner, Charles Longstreet.; White, E. B. (Elwyn Brooks), 1899-1985.; Wichers, W. C. (Willard C.); Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975.; Wilgress, Leolyn Dana, 1892-1969; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Williams, Harrison A.; Wiskemann, Geneva K.; Wolcott, Jesse Paine, 1893-1969.; Woodside, Willson.; Wyatt, Wilson W. (Wilson Watkins), 1905-1996; Young, Stephen M. (Stephen Marvin), 1889-1984.
Genre Terms:
Ambrotypes.; Diaries.; Paintings.; Photographs.; Videotapes.
- Biographical
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    (see also box 28)
- Correspondence
  - Fragmentary (Box 1)
  - circa 1922-1932, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - 1916-1921, 22 folders (Box 1)
  - 1922-June 1925, 31 folders (Box 1-a)
  - July 1925-1944, 26 folders (Box 1-b)
  - 1945-September 1950, 35 folders (Box 2)
  - October 1950-August 1954, 43 folders (Box 3)
  - September 1954-September 1957, 36 folders (Box 4)
  - October 1957-December 1958, 43 folders (Box 5)
  - 1959, 51 folders (Box 6)
  - January-August 1960, 39 folders (Box 7)
  - August 1960-July 1961, 41 folders (Box 8)
  - August 1961-September 1962, 36 folders (Box 9)
  - October 1962-February 1964, 36 folders (Box 10)
  - March 1964-June 1966, 38 folders (Box 11)
  - July 1966-June 1969, 40 folders (Box 12)
  - July 1969-1977, 40 folders (Box 13)
- Personal and miscellaneous
  - Correspondence with mother 1960-1962, and letters of condolence upon her death (Box 14)
  - Drafts of letters to newspapers 1934-1946 (Box 14)
  - Drafts of letters to newspapers circa 1946-1970s, 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Memoranda and notes of telephone conversations, 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Schedules and itineraries (Box 14)
  - Notes and report s, 7 folders (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 6 folders (Box 14)
  - Drafts of writings, 9 folders (Box 14)
  - Biographical sketch of Chase S. Osborn by Stella B. Osborn (Box 14)
  - Outline (with some finished chapters) of a projected biography of Chase S. Osborn (Box 14)
  - Papers concerning publication of An Accolade for Chase Osborn, 1940, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Press releases (personal), 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Speeches and public statements (Box 15)
  - Newspaper clippings (re. Stella Osborn), 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Poetry, 8 folders (Box 15)
  - Income tax papers 1961-1968, 8 folders (Box 15)
  - Personal miscellanea, 9 folders (Box 15)
  - Diaries, 1949, 1953, 1956-1971 (Box 16)
    Later diaries will be found in box 33
  - U-M student notebooks and diaries, account books, 1918-1921 (Box 16)
- Atlantic Union Committee and related
  - Chronology of Atlantic Union 1939-1964 (Box 16)
  - Papers 1950-1962, 20 folders (Box 16)
  - Miscellanea
    - Undated, 8 folders (Box 16)
    - 1950, 6 folders (Box 16)
    - 1957 (Box 16)
  - Press releases 1952, 1956-1960, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Justin Blackwelder (Executive Secretary)
    - Papers 1955-1960, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Robert P. Patterson (Vice President)
    - Papers 1949-1959 (Box 18)
  - Owen J. Roberts (President)
    - Papers 1949-1952 (Box 18)
    - Papers concerning endorsement of the Atlantic Union 1951-1953 (Box 18)
  - Walden Moore (Secretary of the Board)
    - Papers 1949-1952 (Box 18)
  - Sabra Holbrook (Public Relations Director)
    - Papers 1948-1951, 19 folders (Box 18)
  - Frank C. Baker (Mrs.)
    - Papers 1950-1953 (Box 18)
  - Chester Wells Clark (Mrs.)
    - Papers 1964 (Box 18)
  - Atlantic Union News 1950-1960, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Atlantic Union News Bulletin 1966-1969 (Box 18)
  - Atlantic Union Herald 1950-January 19, 1951, October 1952, January, 1957 (Box 18)
  - Newsletter, Michigan Branch of Atlantic Union Committee and miscellanea 1953-1956, 1959 (Box 18)
  - Conferences of the Atlantic Union Committee
    - Papers 1950-1952, 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Papers 1953-1955, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Buffalo, New York May 29, 1951 (Box 18)
    - Memphis, Tennessee November 1951 (Box 18)
    - Buffalo, New York 1952, 5 folders (Box 18)
    - Washington, D.C. 1952 (Box 18)
    - Washington, D.C. 1953, 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Philadelphia 1953, 6 folders (Box 18)
    - New York 1955, 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Louisville, Kentucky 1956, 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Washington, D.C. 1958 (Box 18)
    - Springfield, Illinois 1966 (Box 18)
  - Nominations 1955-1960, 5 folders (Box 20)
  - Council formation 1949, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - "Operation Austin" 1951 (Box 20)
  - Resolution and related
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - State Department responses on Atlantic Union resolutions 1950-1960 (Box 20)
    - Senate Concurrent resolution 12 1950, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Senate Concurrent resolution 17 (correspondence about) 1960, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Resolutions (various) (Box 20)
    - Resolutions and drafts 1949 (Box 20)
    - Resolution support 1949 (Box 20)
    - Resolutions, 4 folders (Box 20)
  - NATO clippings, 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Atlantic Union Committee National Council
    - Papers 1952 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence A-Z 1958-1960, 12 folders (Box 20)
  - Free Nation Federation Association 1970-1971 (Box 21)
  - International Association for Federal Union 1968-1972 (Box 21)
  - Federal Union Newsletter" (Box 21)
  - Federal Union agenda and minutes (Box 21)
  - Federal Union form letters and news releases (Box 21)
  - Federal Union bulletins and reports (Box 21)
  - Federal Union miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Freedom and Union news releases (Box 21)
  - Young Citizens' Committee for an Atlantic Convention, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Young Citizens' Committee for Senate Concurrent Resolution 64 (Box 21)
  - Youth for Atlantic Union miscellanea (Box 21)
  - Young Federalists for Atlantic Union, Correspondence 1962, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Young Federalists for Atlantic Union miscellanea (Box 21)
  - Paul Findley 1963-1969 (press releases), 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Clarence Streit papers 1949-1972, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - International Movement for Atlantic Union
    - Bulletins (Box 21)
    - Press releases 1959-1968, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Board minutes and agenda 1958-1965 (Box 21)
    - Treasurer's reports and financial data 1961-1966 (Box 21)
    - Miscellanea, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Atlantic Union Committee membership lists and directory material (Box 21)
  - Atlantic Union and Freedom and Union tracts and pamphlets, 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Freedom and Union tear sheets and reprints undated, 1946-1970, 20 folders (Box 22)
  - Atlantic Union Clippings, 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Freedom and Union, 1950-1972 (Box 22)
    (incomplete)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials concerning Atlantic unity (Box 23)
  - Congressiona1 Record, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - N.A.T.O. miscellanea (Box 24)
  - Atlantic Exploratory Convention 1956 (Box 24)
  - Atlantic Congress 1959 London, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Atlantic Treaty Association 1967, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Atlantic Treaty Association 1969 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Atlantic Union lists, 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Guest book 1963-1970 (Box 25)
- Business and Professional Women's Club
  - Press releases relating to Stella Brunt Osborn (Box 24)
  - International federation 1956-1961 (Box 24)